<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DOME Architecture</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/</link><description>Recent content on DOME Architecture</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/overview/</guid><description>The DOME ecosystem consists of a set of federated marketplaces, replicating the catalogue data among them in a secure way.
The diagram below provides an overview of the core components of DOME.
The core components of DOME
In July 4th 2024, DOME entered into production with a single marketplace instance operated by the DOME Consortium (the dotted rectangle on the left). In the coming months it is expected that other instances of marketplaces, operated by different entities, will start integrating and federating among them to create the DOME ecosystem (one of those federated instances is shown on the right of the diagram).</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/registration/10_overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/registration/10_overview/</guid><description>This is a placeholder page. Content is being created.</description></item><item><title>The LEARCredential</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/learcredential/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/learcredential/</guid><description>The LEARCredential is a machine-readable document representing a Mandate or Powers of Representation. The format used in DOME is a Verifiable Credential using an eIDAS signature to bind the mandate data with the real-world identity of the issuer of the credential.
We base our design in the RPaM-Ontology, which is a project started in 2018 by the Directorate-General for Informatics (DG-DIGIT) of the European Commission, funded by the ISA Programme, to organise and support the development of an ontology about the Representation of Powers and Mandates, from now on the RPaM Ontology.</description></item><item><title>Authentication</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/authentication/</guid><description>DOME uses Verifiable Credentials for authentication and access control of the users interacting with the DOME services.
In this document we describe how you can integrate the DOME authentication mechanism in your own applications. It is very easy.
You do not need to know the underlying technical details to use it, but if you are interested you can look here.
There are two types of users that can authenticate to DOME services:</description></item><item><title>LEARCredential (digital process)</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/registration/lear_digital/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/registration/lear_digital/</guid><description>Go to the DOME Issuer portal The DOME Issuer portal is located at https://dome.mycredential.eu/ and below is an image of the screen.
The site is intended for Legal Representatives of companies who want to issue one or more LEARCredentials to one or more employees of the company. A LEARCredential is a type of Verifiable Credential which enables an employee, nominated by a legal representative, to act on behalf of an organisation with restricted powers with respect to third-parties.</description></item><item><title>LEARCredential (manual process)</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/registration/30_learcredential_manual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/registration/30_learcredential_manual/</guid><description>This is a placeholder page. Content is being created.</description></item><item><title>Powers of Representation</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/registration/40_powers_of_representation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/registration/40_powers_of_representation/</guid><description>This is a placeholder page. Content is being created.</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>