<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Digital Identity on DOME Architecture</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/</link><description>Recent content in Digital Identity on DOME Architecture</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The LEARCredential</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/10_learcredential/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/10_learcredential/</guid><description>The LEARCredential is a machine-readable legal document representing an electonic Mandate (known also as Company Authorization Letter). In this context, the term Mandate is used to describe the concept of delegating specific permissions and powers to an employee of an organisation, enabling that employee to act on behalf of the company in a specific set of matters or tasks. We explicitly focus on the business environment and do not cover natural persons acting as citizens.</description></item><item><title>Authentication</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/20_authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/20_authentication/</guid><description>DOME uses Verifiable Credentials for authentication and access control of the users interacting with the DOME services.
In this document we describe how you can integrate the DOME authentication mechanism in your own applications. It is very easy.
You do not need to know the underlying technical details to use it, but if you are interested you can look here.
There are two types of users that can authenticate to DOME services:</description></item><item><title>Powers</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/30_powers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/30_powers/</guid><description> tmf_type tmf_domain tmf_function tmf_action Description Domain DOME Onboarding Execute Perform the onboarding process in DOME Domain DOME ProductOffering Create Create a ProductOffering in the marketplace Domain DOME ProductOffering Update Update a ProductOffering in the marketplace Domain DOME ProductOffering Delete Delete a ProductOffering in the marketplace Domain DOME Certification Upload Upload a Verifiable Certification to the marketplace, associated to a Product</description></item></channel></rss>