<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Digital Identity on DOME Architecture</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/</link><description>Recent content in Digital Identity on DOME Architecture</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The LEARCredential</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/learcredential/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/learcredential/</guid><description>The LEARCredential is a machine-readable document representing a Mandate or Powers of Representation. The format used in DOME is a Verifiable Credential using an eIDAS signature to bind the mandate data with the real-world identity of the issuer of the credential.
We base our design in the RPaM-Ontology, which is a project started in 2018 by the Directorate-General for Informatics (DG-DIGIT) of the European Commission, funded by the ISA Programme, to organise and support the development of an ontology about the Representation of Powers and Mandates, from now on the RPaM Ontology.</description></item><item><title>Authentication</title><link>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://DOME-Marketplace.github.io/architecture/docs/identity/authentication/</guid><description>DOME uses Verifiable Credentials for authentication and access control of the users interacting with the DOME services.
In this document we describe how you can integrate the DOME authentication mechanism in your own applications. It is very easy.
You do not need to know the underlying technical details to use it, but if you are interested you can look here.
There are two types of users that can authenticate to DOME services:</description></item></channel></rss>